Hello, welcome to the special episode of Learn German in Hindi.
This
episode is important because in this we are going to learn
that in the videos that I have made till now,
how can you learn German for any medical purpose and related to it,
which is very much related to diet,
I will try to answer them, so let's start, first of all many
people had
asked that we had a disagreement that
those videos are with this, this is all fine, I have
uploaded my office videos but classes are
different, so how will we learn them together, so
one thing I don't know is that the
videos are not uploaded randomly, whatever
I have
learnt in this till now, show the clock,
I have uploaded these videos from the same floor, in fact,
when I had classes, it was
twice a week, that means there used to be one or two
matches on Tuesday and Friday, second
generation dad gives a gap of two days to three days in a week,
similarly my
videos were uploaded, if you remember,
I used to upload videos on Wednesday and Sunday, so
if  If you want to study from this then you are preparing for
cancer, you can do it on a simple app,
consider that you have put on a glass and
decide once and promise that you will not do it and then in
your first day you will learn a
concept, next time the next three
days you will do that concept, you
can watch the video again,
next day make your own 5 sentences on it,
then on the fourth day a new concept,
you have to learn two concepts in a week,
if you keep doing this then in total 6
months you will reach the peak, it is simple,
print this tempered glass, if
you give it a pattern to a cup then it will become easy for you, do
not do this, you will understand it at that time
but will forget it later,
two concepts in a week, five sentences every day
are clear, the second question people ask me a lot is that is it
interactive, right, whatever
you do is interactive,
so the first thing if you watch, that is
why I told that my videos are completely
interactive, learn as you like  I am
taking classes, many people have
asked me that it is simple, did they understand it, so
when I say it happened
in the videos because I taught it in the same way as
I learned in my classes, other
questions about it, our doubts were also answered,
for that we have admin news, one you
can write your output in the comment section, you
can ask your questions on the FD I have taken in the gym, I
always try to answer all your doubts within two days, if there
is any important, any concept is different, then
I come live on every first and third Wednesday of the month, then I
can answer your questions, so
if clearing your doubts is an issue, then
for us after that we have
revenue for that too and one thing that comes in people's mind is
that they want to roam, right now how do you
know that I don't believe in the concept, it has happened,
if you want to learn from your heart, then this is very
simple and what are you doing, my people who are
Maithili, that job  Conception make 5 sentences on it
Sapoch means first
you will remember this video, what is taught in it that you have to
make a simple sentence, this is
obscene, so today make 5 sentences, the next day
five new lawyers and Pathak-Path Central, then you
learned your name, say the spelling of your name,
your friend's name, the name of your village,
after that number C, then I will give
you its trick, see this watch, when
you say time GK time, datesheet,
then when you go to mode V, you will see the original,
you must have found the first peelan spieler cricket a
bit hard, Punjab mode, and if I
further peel its cricket, then you will remember
and how many such sentences can you make,
diabetic patient, you can make anything, for that
no one needs to give you that sentence for mode V and
as you go ahead, in which speed santa
said first spinner award will be given, but do it once,
then once Sapoch,
in the question, percentage cricket has come, so you break it so many times,
crispy learn means you will be able to play it.  If you are
understanding then that is why
when you use this app in the first place then the task
seems very hard but on the fourth one it seems that it will be done in the same way so don't worry that
five new centers at a set every day, this
is enough for you, just reach there immediately, many
people are angry, girls, very common
question is whether these videos are enough, can I do
average B1 with these videos, then I will answer it like this that
this method is enough, means by this method, whatever
I have taught in these 4556 videos,
and by making my 5 sentences every day,
many of my students have got
very good scores in 1821, so you are
understanding it, then this proven
quality of these videos is very important
that self study in this, you make
your sentences every day
and it will not happen by watching these videos, but
if you go into it from here, watch the video,
make your 5 sentences every day, do self
study like this, then
definitely this  There is
no need to compromise on the quality of the video. Okay, so the next
question is better than that, and I think its answer is
very important. If this video
is such a good economist,
why don't you charge for it? Because nowadays there is so much
commercialization of education that
people feel that if something is big then it
means it must be inferior. So understand that
everyone has an edge in life. So my
game is that whoever wants to learn German should get to
learn it. Till now, whoever has a
hotel or who lives in the metro
or whoever can organize classes can
go to the hotel or organize classes anywhere else and
learn German. But whoever does not have these resources
available should also get to learn German. This is
my country. And that is why I wanted to do this. Even
when I actually took classes
online, I used to take them at that time. Till date, I have
not earned even ₹1 from teaching German.
And that is why if you have any doubt in your mind, then
remove that also that he
teaches at a lower level here, where else does he
teach more, which I have  It comes, I have
taught it in videos with highest
quality, I can say in summary like this that
everyone feels that
we should give something back to the society, so in this is my way of giving back everything that the
society has done for me, so this is
my attempt to do that,
you can understand from this, so please don't think that
Baba, it is free, so how will its quality be,
so coming to the next question, the
next is how do we practice it,
okay, so first of all how do people study that, so
first of all
if you see in our video itself, then
we have a 250 year old son episode,
total, if you have said that
this will become your force and if
you want to increase the duration of your practice, then
consistency in life,
keep a note book every day for five minutes, that today
you have to grind transportation, tight
quotation for transportation theme people and
backward people, what do you call bus, what do you call train, what do you call
aeroplane, what do you call
car, what do you call cycle,
you must have world and if  It is
possible to make sentences, if not the
world, just write five words every day, if you
learn then in 6 months you will earn more than
words and this is 500, it is a little bit of a very good
competition, don't worry about
vocabulary, instead of competition, I will
memorize 50 words a day, you will not remember them and if you do
not remember them with the content then you will
forget them, so don't worry about that, learn
five words every day from your own content and
okay, the second thing would be
how to practice garlic and urine,
listening to yourself, so for that I
say, when I was studying years
ago, then there were very few resources, nowadays
with this project of internet, so
mini resources, my favorite is Deutsche Welle,
Deutsche Welle's website and YouTube channel,
you will find so much complex on them, you will get tired, the
tariff will not end like this, Prince
spoon, I mean, you can see now by going there,
from level seven to even one,
now as much material as
you want is available to you, if you want  There are many
other websites as well. Let's discuss this topic.
People
ask me, "Which book should I use?" My
method is unique to everyone. In
my opinion, that book is
n't necessary. I believe that if
you understand what I'm teaching properly
and create five of your own content every day,
that's enough. If you use it, there are
many books from various publications that you
can use. My only concern is that often, the
hunger is German,
and because of that, people get a little tense, or
demoralized. So,
after that, do whatever you want. Use whatever app you
want during the day, and you'll use it. The
director doesn't stop at anything. There are so
many websites and
YouTube channels where you can
learn. Learn what it is. We should know
German at a certain level, or a little
more than that. Then, from where it
comes, it doesn't matter to us. Whatever
material you use, you can use it.  It's good but their
crunch is what I have kept, if you leave mine and do
flop flop flop then this is how
cricket became the most popular, followed by laser and
humor, then comes Shravan, so we
practice writing 500 sentences every day
and then comes special, many people say
then I don't know how to speak, so when will you be able to speak,
when
people say this, then your lips should be level, so
make your own short sentences, that my
request is that I want to eat this, so in
this Addison, keep making such short
sentences, now keep speaking in your mind, keep speaking
with Meerut, if when your
A2 is about to end, you are also starting one
and if you are not able to find a partner,
try to get if any of your
Apple friends is learning with you,
if you are not able to find one, then email me on my email ID,
I will try to find a partner for you,
but trust me, I have
not had a very good experience with this, people
give names in excitement and then
when they start speaking, then they do not come
to speak, there is a problem
history, so the partner should come and be off committed, that there is
no opportunity right now, speak German to me
If you want to learn, if you feel that you have
reached the first level then only email me, I will try my best to give you my best
and finally,
many people have exam
related questions, so for that
I have already made videos, I have
made a method for that, now you can go and watch that playlist, your
doubts will be cleared, in
fact, now
I have made many such playlists, if there is a case, cut
conjunctions, I have made a playlist for the exam, if you want to
revise the questions, then now you
can go and watch that playlist also, so
I hope that now you have understood
how you can learn German with my videos
and all your doubts must have been cleared,
if not, then you
can write your questions in the comments or you can email me,
it is always important to clear your
doubts, thank you.